Guide to the Abraham Joshua Heschel Papers, 1880, 1919-1998 and undated RL.10086
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1880, 1921-1990s and undated; 6; 245 Boxes
  - Notes, 1880, circa 1930s-1970s and undated; 10
    - [Miscellaneous notes], 1952-1954; 2 of 2 (Box 207, Folder 9)
    - RA, 1952-1954 (Box 207, Folder 10)
      Primarily handwritten notes with some clippings and correspondence related to Judaism.
    - Quotes, 1952-1955; 1 of 2 (Box 208, Folder 1)
      Handwritten notes and fragments that are quotes related to a multitude of topics.
    - Quotes, 1952-1955; 2 of 2 (Box 208, Folder 2)
    - Lemberger, 1953 (Box 208, Folder 3)
      Contains a Yiddish letter, some handwritten notes, and some negative reproductions of Hebrew manuscripts.
    - [Miscellaneous materials], 1953 (Box 208, Folder 4)
      Contains the handwritten Hebrew text of an allocution about Rabbi Israel Friedman of Ruzhuyn, handwritten notes about a variety of topics, and Yiddish paper clippings.
    - [Miscellaneous notes], 1953 (Box 208, Folder 5)
      Contains handwritten notes on a variety of topics including grandeur, the sublime, Jewish law, religious individualism, and joy.
    - ר‛ צדוק, 1953 (Box 208, Folder 6)
      Transliteration: R[abbi] Tsadoḳ
      Translation: Rabbi Tzadok
      Contains miscellaneous Hebrew handwritten notes, citations of Talmudic passages and of English and German scholarship on Jewish history, two corrected copies of a Hebrew typescript, and a different Hebrew typescript of parenetic content. It also contains a Yiddish letter from Rabbi Leo Jung.
    - טעמי המצוות, 1953 (Box 208, Folder 7)
      Transliteration: Ta'amei HaMitzvot
      Translation: Reasons for the Commandments
      Mix of handwritten notes on a wide variety of topics, roughly centered on Mitzvot (commandments) and their various interpretations.
    - טעמי מצות, 1953, 1956 (Box 208, Folder 8)
      Transliteration: Ta'amei Mitzvot
      Translation: Reasons for Commandments
      Mix of handwritten and typed notes on a variety of topics including the actions of G, his will and his wisdom, and formulism.
    - II Good-evil, 1953-1954 (Box 208, Folder 9)
      Includes notes and typescripts on a variety of subjects, including Man, prayer, ineffable, suffering, Niebuhr, freedom, evil.
    - Niebuhr, 1953-1956 (Box 208, Folder 10)
      Mix of handwritten notes and typescripts related to evil and sin as they pertain to man and an analysis of some of Niebuhr's writings. Also includes a partial typed manuscript with "Niebuhr" written on the front page.
    - [Miscellaneous notes and writings], 1953-1958; 1 of 4 (Box 209, Folder 1)
      Mix of handwritten notes, fragments, notecards, typed lectures, annotated typescripts, and clippings on a variety of theological topics and concepts.
    - [Miscellaneous notes and writings], 1953-1958; 2 of 4 (Box 209, Folder 2)
    - [Miscellaneous notes and writings], 1953-1958; 3 of 4 (Box 209, Folder 3)
    - [Miscellaneous notes and writings], 1953-1958; 4 of 4 (Box 209, Folder 4)
    - [Contemporary world], 1954 (Box 209, Folder 5)
      Contains typed and handwritten notes about the contemporary condition and Hebrew citations, as well as a long handwritten Hebrew text about medicine.
    - Dogma, 1954 (Box 209, Folder 6)
      Mix of handwritten notes, fragments, and typescripts on a variety of topics including the Torah, understanding, and literature.
    - הלכה - אגדה, 1954 (Box 209, Folder 7)
      Transliteration: Halakhah - Agadah
      Translation: Law - Aggadah
      Primarily handwritten notes and fragments on a wide variety of theological topics related to Halakhah and Aggadah.
    - הלכה – אגדה, 1954 (Box 209, Folder 8)
      Contains numerous handwritten notes and notecards on themes of halacha and aggadah.
    - Limits of Reason - Inexpressible, 1954 (Box 209, Folder 9)
      Primarily handwritten notes related to the topic of reason. Themes include reason's limits, limits of Moses and Aristotle, and prophecy of reason.
    - [Man], 1954 (Box 209, Folder 10)
      Primarily handwritten notes and fragments related to the topic of man. Some materials are clipped into sub-themes such as evil, salvation, and original sin.
    - [Miscellaneous notes], 1954 (Box 210, Folder 1)
      Handwritten notes and fragments on a variety of topics including faith, polarity and mystery.
    - [Miscellaneous notes], 1954 (Box 210, Folder 2)
      Handwritten notes and fragments on a variety of theological and philosophical topics.
    - בעשט, circa 1954, 1956 (Box 210, Folder 3)
      Transliteration: Besht [Baal Shem Tov]
      Translation: Baal Shem Tov
      A mix of handwritten notes and correspondence related to The Baal Shem Tov, Hasidism and Hasidic rabbis. Includes a number of bibliographic notecards.
    - אמונה, 1954-1955 (Box 210, Folder 4)
      Transliteration: Emunah
      Translation: Faith
      Handwritten notes on a variety of topics including the relationship of man to God, faith, and virtue.
    - [Miscellaneous notes], 1954-1956 (Box 210, Folder 5)
      Primarily handwritten notes on a variety of topics including piety and prayer. Also includes a poster for New Lights and Old Shadows by Lionel S. Reiss which includes Heschel's appreciation for the book.
    - Man: CCAR, 1954-1957; 1 of 2 (Box 210, Folder 6)
      Primarily handwritten notes, Bible verses, and citations all related to the topic of Man. Some materials are clipped into sub-themes such as awareness of sin, man as a symbol, and worship.
    - Man: CCAR, 1954-1957; 2 of 2 (Box 210, Folder 7)
    - In need of man, circa 1955 (Box 210, Folder 8)
      Mix of annotated typescripts, handwritten notes, and fragments on the topic of God in need of Man.
    - Integrity C, 1955-1956 (Box 210, Folder 9)
      Mix of handwritten and typescript notes related to the topic of integrity.
    - Intellectualism, 1956 (Box 211, Folder 1)
      Mix of handwritten and typed notes related to the topic of intellectualism. Themes include philosophy of religion, intellectual revolution, and religious intellectualism.
    - מבוא --, 1956 (Box 211, Folder 2)
      Transliteration: Mavo --
      Translation: Introduction --
      Handwritten notes on a variety of topics including metaphorical, ambiguity and confusion. Possibly notes for a class.
    - Prophets: Prophets, 1956 (Box 211, Folder 3)
      Mix of handwritten and typed notes on a variety of topics including revelation, chastisement, and God's co-suffering. Many of the notes appear to be citations or quotes from other sources.
    - Reformation, 1956 (Box 211, Folder 4)
      Mix of handwritten notes on a variety of topics. Also includes typescript for pamphlet "Advocacy for the book 'Mishna Torah'" by A.S. Halkin.
    - [Miscellaneous], 1956, 1962 (Box 211, Folder 5)
      Mix of handwritten notes, quotes, Bible verses, clippings, and citations. Includes a letter to Heschel requesting clarification of specific quotations in God in Search of Man.
    - Heschel 663, 1956, 1966 (Box 211, Folder 6)
      Mix of materials including handwritten notes, lecture notes, and notecards on a variety of topics. Also includes a student papers and a typescript "The Bible - Antiquated and Contemporary" by Dr. James A. Sanders.
    - חשוב, 1956-1957 (Box 211, Folder 7)
      Primarily handwritten notes and fragments clipped together in thematic bundles including Demonic, Today, and Man. Also contains a small amount of administrative correspondence.
    - [Spirit], 1956-1957 (Box 211, Folder 8)
      Primarily handwritten notes related to the topic of the spirit, including spiritual illiteracy and the spirit of the Torah.
    - Misc., 1956-1958 (Box 211, Folder 9)
      Contains mostly handwritten Hebrew notes about Jewish books and Hasidism. Also contains a photocopy of the title page of the books Minchah meracheshet and Hasidim mesaprim, a mail receipt, an invitation for the Yahrzeit of the father of the Grand Rabbi Rabinowitz, the publisher's ad for a book, and Yiddish paper clippings.
    - Prophets: [Miscellaneous notes], 1956-1960; 1 of 2 (Box 212, Folder 1)
      Contains handwritten notes and fragments on a variety of topics, mainly short thoughts by Heschel and assorted Talmudic quotations.
    - Prophets: [Miscellaneous notes], 1956-1960; 2 of 2 (Box 212, Folder 2)
    - לא בשמים היא, 1957; 1 of 2 (Box 212, Folder 3)
      Transliteration: Lo ba-shamayim hi
      Translation: Not in Heaven
      Handwritten notes and notecards. Topics include man and the universe, faith and reason, and Hebrew words.
    - לא בשמים היא, 1957; 2 of 2 (Box 212, Folder 4)
    - מסודר, 1957, 1961 (Box 212, Folder 5)
      Transliteration: Mesudar
      Translation: Ordered
      Contains handwritten notes about a variety of Jewish topics (including free will and theophanies), as well as a three-page English typed text by Ernest F. Scott, D.D. on "Apocalyptic Christianity."
    - Calendar, 1957, 1963 (Box 212, Folder 6)
      Mix of reports, clippings, and handwritten notes regarding calendar reform.
    - הוספות לכרך א, 1957-1959; 1 of 2 (Box 212, Folder 7)
      Transliteration: Hosafot le-kerekh alef
      Translation: Additions to volume 1
      Contains handwritten notes about a variety of Jewish topics, with fragments and citations.
    - הוספות לכרך א, 1957-1959; 2 of 2 (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - מצות, 1957-1960; 1 of 3 (Box 213, Folder 2)
      Transliteration: Mitsṿot
      Translation: Precepts
      Contains handwritten notes about a variety of religious topics (including some not directly related to Judaism, such as Buddhism or late ancient religions).
    - מצות, 1957-1960; 2 of 3 (Box 213, Folder 3)
    - מצות, 1957-1960; 3 of 3 (Box 213, Folder 4)
    - הוספות לכרך א :Books, 1958; 1 of 4 (Box 213, Folder 5)
      Contains handwritten notes (some on notecards) about a variety of religious (mostly Jewish) topics, with many fragments and citations.
    - הוספות לכרך א :Books, 1958; 2 of 4 (Box 213, Folder 6)
    - הוספות לכרך א :Books, 1958; 3 of 4 (Box 213, Folder 7)
    - הוספות לכרך א :Books, 1958; 4 of 4 (Box 213, Folder 8)
    - חסידות ספרים, 1958 (Box 214, Folder 1)
      Transliteration: Ḥasidut Sefarim
      Translation: Hasidism Books
      Handwritten notes and clippings related to Hasidism and Hasidism books.
    - גבולי משה, 1958; 1 of 3 (Box 214, Folder 2)
      Transliteration: Gevule Mosheh
      Translation: Moses's limits
      Contains handwritten notes about Moses.
    - גבולי משה, 1958; 2 of 3 (Box 214, Folder 3)
    - גבולי משה, 1958; 3 of 3 (Box 214, Folder 4)
    - ר"ע ור"י, 1958 (Box 214, Folder 5)
      Transliteration: R[abbi] 'A[qiba] we-r[abbi] I[shma'el]
      Translation: Rabbi Aqiba and Rabbi Ishmael
      Contains handwritten notes about rabbinic Judaism.
    - קטעים, 1958 (Box 214, Folder 6)
      Transliteration: Ḳeṭaʻim
      Translation: Sections
      A mix of handwritten notes and typescripts. Topics include the covenant between God and man, the soul of man, Israel, love and wickedness. Includes a draft of a letter to David Ben Gurion.
    - [Miscellaneous Notes], circa 1958 (Box 214, Folder 7)
      Mix of handwritten notes, fragments, and typescripts related to prayer. Contains a large number of quote from the Talmud, the Bible and elsewhere. Also includes excerpt from an article Heschel wrote for B'nai Brith Monthly entitled "How Judaism Differs from Christianity."
    - חסידות, 1958-1962 (Box 214, Folder 8)
      Transliteration: Ḥasidut
      Translation: Hasidism
      Correspondence, clipplings and handwritten notes related to Hasidism. Includes 4 letters marked "Bloch."
    - Varia, 1959 (Box 215, Folder 1)
      Mix of handwritten notes and typescripts primarily related to man in the image of God. Also includes a typed partial draft with 4 chapters titled "Mystery of Man", "The Shekinah", "Mystic Experiences", and "The Torah - A Mystic Reality."
    - [Miscellaneous], 1959 and undated (Box 215, Folder 2)
      Contains typed notes on the topic of Success, a typed letter "Douglas and Dorothy Steere's Travel Letter #2", and an article in German about Schlomo Carlebach.
    - צורך גבוה - אתדל"ע (= אתערותא דלעילא), circa 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 215, Folder 3)
      Transliteration: Tsorekh gavoha - It['aruta] del'e[ila]
      Translation: A high need - Awakening from above
      Primarily handwritten notes related to the topic of prayer. Also contains some annotated galley pages from Man is Not Alone.
    - צורך גבוה - אתדל"ע (= אתערותא דלעילא), circa 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 215, Folder 4)
    - [Active Intellect], circa 1950s (Box 215, Folder 5)
      Handwritten notes related to the topic of active intellect. Themes include critique of man and blissfulness.
    - Adverbs, circa 1950s (Box 215, Folder 6)
      Handwritten notes and annotated typescripts related to the immanence of God.
    - Bible, circa 1950s (Box 215, Folder 7)
      Primarily handwritten notes related to the topic of the Bible. Also includes a list of questions and answers from a seminar presumably given by Heschel.
    - ביבליוגרפיה, circa 1950s (Box 215, Folder 8)
      Transliteration: Bibliografyah
      Translation: Bibliography
      Contains handwritten notes and bibliographical annotations.
    - Carlebach, circa 1950s (Box 215, Folder 9)
      Contains many orderly handwritten notes and bibliographical references, most of which alphabetically arranged, about the history of Hasidism. Also contains two letters.
    - Earth, circa 1950s (Box 216, Folder 1)
      Mix of handwritten notes and articles related to Jewish Ghettos of the world. Also contains an issue of the publication "Congress Weekly" and a booklet about the Shanghai Ghetto titled "מירער ישיבה אין גלות."
    - חנוך: Education, circa 1950s (Box 216, Folder 2)
      Transliteration: Ḥinukh
      Translation: Education
      Language(s): Most materials in German and Hebrew.
      Primarily handwritten notes all related to education, learning and teaching.
    - Education: RA Education, circa 1950s (Box 216, Folder 3)
      Mix of handwritten notes and corrected/annotated typescript related to Jewish learning and faith.
    - Empathy, circa 1950s (Box 216, Folder 4)
      Primarily handwritten notes and fragments related to the topic of empathy. Includes a handwritten outline with page numbers.
    - Freedom, circa 1950s (Box 216, Folder 5)
      Handwritten notes related to freedom. Includes an article from "The Journal of General Education" with Marshall Meyer's signature on the front cover.
    - חסידות, circa 1950s (Box 216, Folder 6)
      A mix of correspondence, typescripts, handwritten notes and clippings related to Hasidism. Includes short reflections on evil, study, Yom Kippur and the Sabbath. Includes a letter from Grand Rabbi Sh. C. Rubin Halberstam.
    - Intuition, circa 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 216, Folder 7)
      Contains handwritten notes on a variety of topics, including avenues of understanding in Judaism and prophecy.
    - Intuition, circa 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 216, Folder 8)
    - Israel/Principles, circa 1950s (Box 217, Folder 1)
      Mix of annotated typescripts and handwritten notes related to Israel. Also includes copies of Heschel's article "To Be A Jew: What Is It?" from the Zionist Quarterly which have been clipped (sometimes into pieces) and annotated.
    - Jewish Prayer, circa 1950s (Box 217, Folder 2)
      Primarily handwritten notes and fragments related to the topic of Jewish prayer.
    - סוף דבר -- לא חשוב, circa 1950s (Box 217, Folder 3)
      Transliteration: Sof Davar -- Lo Ḥashuv
      Translation: Epilogue -- Not Important
      Contains assorted handwritten notes on a variety of theological subjects, including Maimonides
    - למברגר, circa 1950s; 1 of 3 (Box 217, Folder 4)
      Transliteration: Lemberger
      Includes assorted handwritten notes and typescript notes on various rabbinical books and treatises, including "Ohel Moshe," "Amri Bina," "Amri Tzrofe," "Beit Shlomo," and others.
    - למברגר, circa 1950s; 2 of 3 (Box 217, Folder 5)
    - למברגר, circa 1950s; 3 of 3 (Box 217, Folder 6)
      Includes assorted handwritten notes and typescript notes on a large variety of rabbinical books and treatises, examples include "Ohel Moshe," "Amri Bina," "Amri Tzrofe," "Beit Shlomo," and a few dozen others.
    - Lit, circa 1950s (Box 217, Folder 7)
      Primarily handwritten notes and fragments on a variety of topics including training and habit.
    - שונות: טעמי מצוה, circa 1950s (Box 217, Folder 8)
      Transliteration: Shonot: Ṭaʻame mitsṿah
      Translation: Miscellaneous: Taste of Mitzvah
      Handwritten notes and fragments on a variety of topics including doing, Mitzvah, and autonomy.
    - [Miscellaneous], circa 1950s (Box 217, Folder 9)
      Contains assorted handwritten notes on a variety of theological subjects.
    - [Miscellaneous], circa 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 218, Folder 1)
      Mix of handwritten notes, typed lecture notes, typed parables and corrected typescripts related to a wide variety of topics including reflections on freedom, who is man, problems, and the mitzvah.
    - [Miscellaneous], circa 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 218, Folder 2)
    - שונות, לא חשוב לספר, circa 1950s (Box 218, Folder 3)
      Transliteration: Shonot, Lo ḥashuv le Sefer
      Translation: Miscellaneous, Not important for the Book
      Mostly handwritten notes and fragments related to prayer.
    - [Miscellaneous notes], circa 1950s (Box 218, Folder 4)
      Mix of handwritten notecards and handwritten and typed notes related to a variety of topics including messianism, faith, and the Bible.
    - [Miscellaneous notes], circa 1950s (Box 218, Folder 5)
      Contains a variety of handwritten notes about many topics, as well as bibliographical notes (many of which in Polish). Also contains a letter draft in English and a letter in Yiddish.
    - לשמה, circa 1950s (Box 218, Folder 6)
      Transliteration: Li-shema
      Translation: Name/Title
      Handwritten notes on index cards on theme "lishma" and other assorted notes, including on theme of integrity.
    - מסודר, circa 1950s (Box 218, Folder 7)
      Contains handwritten notes about a variety of topics related to the Torah.
    - [?] מתווין, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 1)
      Transliteration: Ma'atvi'in
      Translation: [Outline?]
      Primarily handwritten notes on a variety of topics including philosophy of Judaism, philosophy of religion, and poetry. Also contains a printed text about Jewish ritual.
    - שבחי הבעש"ט, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 2)
      Transliteration: Shivḥe ha-Beshṭ
      Translation: Praise for the Baal Shem Tov
      Contains notes related to the book Shivchei ha-Besht (Praise for The Baal Shem Tov).
    - Prayer: Essence of Prayer, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 3)
      Primarily handwritten notes related to the essence of prayer.
    - כונה: Prayer, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 4)
      Transliteration: Kavanah
      Translation: Intention
      Primarily handwritten notes related to the topic of prayer.
    - Prayer: Unutterable, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 5)
      Primarily handwritten notes related to prayer, the formulation of prayer and prayers of the heart.
    - Professor A.J. Heschel, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 6)
      Mix of handwritten and typed notes on a variety of topics including intellect, science, philosophy, Aristotle, and man.
    - Prophets, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 7)
      Handwritten notes related to the prophets. Topics include pathos and eschatology, freedom, deeds, and man's relevance to God.
    - Quotes, circa 1950s (Box 219, Folder 8)
      Contains handwritten notes related to a variety of religious topics, such as atonement, hiding, callousness, knowledge of God, and original sin.
    - Quotes, circa 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 220, Folder 1)
      Contains a variety of handwritten notes, including many citations, concerning a variety of topics related to the Torah.
    - Quotes, circa 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 220, Folder 2)
    - ר׳ נחמן הורודנקי, circa 1950s (Box 220, Folder 3)
      Transliteration: Rabbi Naḥman Horodenka
      Translation: Rabbi Nachman of Horodenka
      Contains handwritten notes about R. Nachman of Horodenka and his court, grandfather of R. Nachman of Breslov. Materials also on R. Baruch of Kosov and R. Nachman of Kosov.
    - ר. גרשון, circa 1950s (Box 220, Folder 4)
      Transliteration: R. Gershon
      Translation: Rabbi Gershon
      A mix of handwritten notes, correspondence, annotated typescripts and bibliographic references related to Hasidism and Hasidic rabbis.
    - Rev Continuum, circa 1950s (Box 220, Folder 5)
      Mix of handwritten notes, fragments, and typescripts on a variety of topics including halacha and commitment.
    - בעשט - שונות, circa 1950s (Box 220, Folder 6)
      Transliteration: Beshṭ - Shonot
      Translation: The Baal Shem Tov - Various
      Contains handwritten notes related to The Baal Shem Tov and a long report on the book Amud ha-avodah.
    - תורה והקב"ה, circa 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 220, Folder 7)
      Transliteration: Torah ve-ha-Ka[dosh] Ba[ruch] Hu
      Translation: The Torah and the the Holy One, blessed be He
      Contains handwritten notes, mostly citations from the Talmud, mostly concerning the relationship between God and the Torah.
    - תורה והקב"ה, circa 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 220, Folder 8)
      Contains handwritten notes, mostly citations from the Talmud, concerning the relationship between God and the Torah.
    - עד הנשואים, circa 1950s (Box 221, Folder 1)
      Transliteration: ʻAd ha-niśuʼim
      Translation: The wedding witness
      Contains handwritten notes mostly about Ukrainian Jewry. Also contains an English letter from the National Geographic Society.
    - שלישי: Quotes, circa 1950s (Box 221, Folder 2)
      Transliteration: Shelishi
      Translation: Third
      Mix of handwritten notes and fragments consisting of quotes on a multitude of topics including inspiration, ineffable, insight, and transcendence.
    - Time, circa 1950s (Box 221, Folder 3)
      Mix of handwritten notes and typescripts primarily related to time. Some materials clipped into sub-themes such as image, idolization of man, and Niebuhr.
    - Value, circa 1950s (Box 221, Folder 4)
      Primarily handwritten notes related to the broad theme of values. Materials are bundled into smaller themes including Insecurity of Freedom, obey/choose, and time.
    - [Various notes on Hasidism], circa 1950s (Box 221, Folder 5)
      Contains notes and clippings about a variety of topics related to Hasidism.
    - Man, circa 1950s, 1973 (Box 221, Folder 6)
      Mix of handwritten and typed notes related to the topic of Man. Themes include Man the Symbol of G-d, etymology, and the image of man. Also includes a copy of the 1920 and 1930 Census for Sylvia Heschel.
    - הוספות, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 221, Folder 7)
      Contains handwritten notes about a variety of Jewish topics.
    - אגדה, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 222, Folder 1)
      Contains handwritten and typed notes on themes of aggadah and law, among others.
    - לה חשובArchive III: I, circa 1950s-1960s; 1 of 2 (Box 222, Folder 2)
      Includes a variety of materials: assorted handwritten notes, bibliographic entries, and Talmudic quotations, with topics including intellect and compassion, holiness, God and the Jewish people, prophetism, Avot d'Rabbi Natan, Rabbis Ishmael, Yosi and Shmuel.
    - לה חשובArchive III: I, circa 1950s-1960s; 2 of 2 (Box 222, Folder 3)
    - בין אדם לחברו, circa 1950s-1960s; 1 of 3 (Box 222, Folder 4)
      Transliteration: Ben Adam la-Ḥavero
      Translation: Between One and One's Fellow
      Contains handwritten and typed notes on themes of honor between people, prayer, righteousness and law, the way of peace, and other moral issues.
    - בין אדם לחברו, circa 1950s-1960s; 2 of 3 (Box 222, Folder 5)